Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod.
My name is Marco.
My name is Catherine and today we
have an elementary level lesson for you.
That's right today we're going to
take a look at our mobile phones but not
the physical phone. Now
we're going to talk about
services that you can
get for your mobile phone.
All right so in America
and many other places
you don't buy that little
card with money on it.
You actually have to pay
every month for a service.
So we're going to learn about this today.
Let's check out our dialogue.
[Music]
Telco Mobile how can I help you?
Yes I'd like to activate my
voicemail service please.
Certainly sir. We
currently have a special
promotion where we
include voicemail services,
call waiting and also
three-way calling.
Sure that sounds great
are there any other fees?
Not at all. No hidden
fees or surcharges it is a
flat monthly rate. Perfect.
I also wanted to know
if there's any call
forwarding service.
I am usually out of town
and would like my call to be
forwarded to a local
member. Yes of course we
can activate all these
services in about an hour.
All right we're back
so now let's take a look
at some of these services
on language takeaway.
Language takeaway. So
Marco the first word that
I wanted to talk about
today is this verb to activate.
That's right we have
a verb here to activate.
In this means to make something
start to work to make something begin.
That's right so to turn on
but you don't say hey can you
activate the light? You
wouldn't say that you say
can you turn on the
light but to activate means
to start a service. That's right.
So this is what we want today.
We want to activate
some services
and the first one that we
ask for is voicemail service.
Voice mail service.
Now let's think about the
words that make up this one word.
Voice mail. Voice mail so it's
like a mailbox for your phone.
That's right where you leave
messages obviously not text
messages but you leave voice messages.
That's right so you know I'm sorry I
cannot answer the phone right now please
leave a message after the beep.
That's my voicemail message.
That's right so it's
actually a very useful thing.
We'll talk about that a little bit later
but let's take a look at our next service.
We also want to
get call waiting.
All right so this is a very
interesting service. I don't know if
they have this in other
parts of the world but in
America if I'm talking on
the phone to you Marco
or having a nice conversation
but then my mom calls.
When I'm talking I hear
beep beep beep I hear
some sounds and that means
someone else is trying to call you.
That's right. All right
so you can't hear
this but I can hear
this and that means if I
want to talk to my mom
I'll say hey Marco listen
someone else is calling
can I call you tomorrow.
That's right so actually
call waiting is a very
useful service because
the person that's calling
you will never get a
busy signal. You'll always
seem available but the
good thing is that you
can switch between
calls. So I could say hey
Marco listen I think that's my
mom can you hold can you wait.
I will be right back and then I push a
button and then I can talk to my mom and
then my mom says
okay I'll talk to you later I
push a button and
then Marco you're there.
That's right. That's right
very useful service as well.
Now let's take a look at
our next service that we
are also getting as part
of this package we are
getting three-way calling.
So from the name of this
we can think of three
people talking all right so
maybe Marco you want
to talk to my mom too.
That's right. So we can talk
and then we add another person
so you can call a third
phone number one two
three me you and someone
else and the three of us
can talk at the same
time. That's right so it's
kind of a way of having a small
conference between three people.
That's right. And so this is this is what
you can do with three-way calling you
can call two people
simultaneously and talk to
them at the same time.
So a lot of great services
here I think we've learned
a couple of different things.
Why don't we review it and
listen to the dialogue again.
Telco Mobile how can I help you?
Yes I'd like to activate my
voicemail service please.
Certainly sir. We
currently have a special
promotion where we
include voicemail services,
call waiting and also
three-way calling.
Sure that sounds great.
Are there any other fees?
Not at all. No hidden
fees or surcharges.
It is a flat monthly rate.
Perfect. I also wanted to
know if there's any
call forwarding service.
I am usually out of town
and would like my calls to
be forwarded to a local
member. Yes of course we
can activate all these
services in about an hour.
All right we're back so
now let's keep on going
here towards the last
half of our dialogue.
Let's take a look at some more
words on language takeaway part two.
Language takeaway. So this first phrase in
language takeaway part two is hidden fees.
That's right. The operator
guarantees that there
are no hidden fees. So
this is usually what we
call the fine print. The
small fees that we don't
really know about. So
they say oh it costs three
dollars a month but you
have small little hidden
fees like if you're late
on a payment they'll
charge you an extra
dollar or if you use the
service too much they'll
charge you another extra dollar.
Right so a fee is
something that you pay.
All right and something that is
hidden means you cannot see it.
And so like you're saying with this example
there are many many conditions many
many different things
rules that we have to
follow and if we don't
follow those rules exactly
then maybe this company
that provides the phone
service will ask us for
more and more money.
That's right and actually
has to do a lot with
our next word where
she said that there are
also no surcharges.
Okay so a surcharge is an
extra amount of money
that you have to pay.
So we say that this service
has no hidden fees or surcharge.
So that means that we don't have to pay
anything additional to what we are paying.
For example some
companies will say okay pay us
ten dollars and you get your
new cell phone phone plan.
But to activate your
service is another five dollars.
So the total price
is 15 dollars and
that's a surcharge that's an
extra fee that you have to pay.
That's right okay and continuing on the
topic of money she says it is a flat monthly
rate a flat monthly rate. Well monthly is
an adverb that tells us how often we pay.
We pay one time every month
but this term flat rate is very
very important and it
happened we use this term a
lot when we're talking
about paying fees.
So a flat rate means it does
not change when you for
example talk more on
the phone. That's right.
So you pay the same amount
every month. That's right a
clear example is probably
your internet service provider.
You pay 20 dollars a
month and that's a flat rate.
If you use the internet 24 hours a day
nothing happens you don't pay more.
If you use it less you still pay
the same amount of money.
So what if I pay 10 dollars
normally but this month
I use the internet a lot and
now I have to pay 15 dollars.
Is that a flat rate? No
no that's not a flat rate.
Okay that's a change that
that changes with my use.
That's right okay and
now let's take a look
at one last service that
this man was also interested
in getting and he says
that he wants to get
a call forwarding service.
He wants to forward
his calls to a local
number. Okay so to forward
something means to pass
it along. So call forwarding
means that if I'm not
available for example
I'm not at home and
someone calls my home.
There's no one there to talk
to the person that's calling.
Then maybe I could have
a call forwarding service
that will make the call
go to my cellular phone.
All right so the call
forwarding means that the call
will travel to another phone.
That's right that's right.
So as you said this is
what call forwarding
is and the word to
forward as you said to pass
along maybe many of you
have done it in your emails
when you get maybe a
nice message you forward it
to more of your friends
and this is the the exact
same definition. Exactly so you have one
message and you pass it on to someone else.
And so call forwarding you
normally have this service if you're
often on business trips or
traveling you're out of town.
That's right. It's
very very helpful for
people who are not in
one place all the time.
That's right so why
don't we listen to the
dialogue one last time
and we'll be back in a bit.
Telco Mobile how can I help you?
Yes I'd like to activate my
voicemail service please.
Certainly sir we
currently have a special
promotion where we
include voicemail services,
call waiting and also
three-way calling.
Sure that sounds great are
there any other fees? Not at all.
No hidden fees or surcharges
it is a flat monthly rate.
Perfect I also wanted
to know if there's
any call forwarding
service. I am usually out
of town and would like
my calls to be forwarded
to a local member.
Yes of course we can
activate all these
services in about an hour.
So talking about all
these services it's very
interesting because
many of these services
are not really available
everywhere in the world
like for example
voicemail. That's right so in
China no one really
has voicemail it's very
strange for an American
because you think well if
I'm not home I want to
know why this person called
but oftentimes you just
have to call back and find out.
That's right and actually I really think
that voicemail service is a very good thing
especially if you need
to leave a message for
someone you know hey
we're at the restaurant coming
back when you have a
chance. But also call waiting
I really really hate to
call someone and have
the busy you know the
busy tone. Yeah and then you
know that they're on the
telephone but you don't
know when they will
stop talking on the phone.
This really annoys me too
especially when I call for
delivery food from a
restaurant. It's like please
answer your phone but maybe
someone's ordering a lot of food.
That's right so actually these services
are very common in the United States
and I'm not sure there
even more services now
I know that you can have
a telephone number for
example in another country
but it'll ring in the United States.
Yeah that's right or you can connect to
your computer and your messaging service and
all these things to
your phone so it's pretty
pretty technologically
advanced but I'm very curious
to know about you guys
are listeners what kind
of services for your cell phone
or for your landline do you have?
Do you have call
forwarding or voicemail?
Let us know our website is englishpa.com.
All right we'll see everyone there. Bye.